YISA, Joseph Adigun

2 Selia Amoke Close, Kongi-Bodija Ibadan, Oyo state 08022243720 | jossyyisa90@yahoo.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

Dedicated and energetic recent graduate of Agricultural Economics and Farm Management (2:1) having 2 years of experience in overseeing farm operations and implementing agricultural practices while working both on the field and in the office. Possess expertise in undertaking research, lecturing, various farm operations including farm crop planting, cultivating, and harvesting along with animal husbandry and personal development. Excellent in leading and working with people, demonstrate interpersonal skills and problem solving for resolving conflict, and establishing relationships. Poised to transition in the services sector by maximizing potentials as a productive and active individual giving quality performance for the attainment of the goal of the organization.

AREAS OF STRENGTH AND EXPERTISE

- **Undertaking Research**
- Creative Problem Solving Pond Management
- Staff Supervision
- Marketing abilities
- Animal Husbandry Management
- Presentation Skills
- Customer Service

- Interpersonal Communication
- Problem Analysis
- Team Leading
- Lecturing

KEY SKILLS ASSESSMENTS

- **Time Management:** Aptitude to work long hours unsupervised, adapting regular skills that assist in promoting effective production, implementing decisions, cooperating, enforcing policies, effective time management, meeting goals, accepting accountability and meeting deadlines.
- **Excellent Communicator:** Excellent oral and written communication skills comprising speaking, writing, listening effectively, expressing ideas and presenting information and editing.
- Organizational & Marketing Skills: Self-disciplined and proactive, generating innovative ideas for enhanced productivity in organizations, good marketing skills, persistent at meeting set targets, capability to work effectively under pressure and with people at various levels.
- * Technical Proficiencies: Highly accomplished and efficient in IT operations including Office Package MS word, MS Excel and MS PowerPoint, SPSS, internet surfing and email.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Federal College of Agriculture Akure **National Youth Service Corp Assignee** (Assistant Lecturer & Farm Supervisor) Dec 2015 - Nov 2016

Deliver lectures to groups of students on Macroeconomics by using advanced teaching techniques. Proficiently administer and instruct students on farm operations and monitor programmes and assessments.

University of Ibadan Fish Farm Trainee (Fish production)

May 2014

Directed all aspects of fish production such as Pond preparation, Brooding, Pond management, fish inventory control, fish cropping and movement; monitored processing and marketing activities, and fish spawning; as well as strong overall multi-task, organizational skills.

Professional Experience Continued...

IAR&T (Moore Plantation, Ibadan), Cocoa Research Institute of Nigeria March 2014 - April 2014 Federal College of Forestry, Forest Research Institute of Nigeria Intern (Research Training & Assistant)

• Collected and analysed, research materials from the field and kept training records and files up to date as well as created PowerPoint Presentations for various training programs.

OFFER Center, Oluponna Osun state Trainee (Crop Production, Animal Husbandry, Personal Development)

Jan 2014 - Feb 2015

- Leveraged education skills for arable and tree crops production including cultivation from land preparation to marketing along with animal feed production.
- Significantly contributed during intensive training on inter and intra personal development with the help of research projects on committee levels, presentations and debates.

Bowen University Teaching and Research farm Trainee (Crop production and Animal husbandry)

June 2013 - Dec 2013

• Performed animal husbandry and crop production functions and daily routine management of poultry and ruminants as well as pond stocking in order to harvest, process and market.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATE

Certificate, National Service, 2016

Bachelor in Agricultural Economics & Farm Management, 2015

Bowen University Iwo, 2015

Nigerian Institute of Management (in view)

Certificate Course on Project Management Practices
Proficiency Course in Microsoft Office Packages
Certificate Course in Emotional Intelligence (EI)

PERSONAL INFORMATION

DATE AND PLACE OF BIRTH, 27st March, 1990, Oyo State
NATIONALITY, Nigerian
STATE OF ORIGIN, Oyo State
LOCAL GOVERNMENT AREA, Ibadan North
MARITAL STATUS, Single